[music]
[Instructor] Cool, so
we've taken our first steps
in fixing this problem
that we created for ourselves
by making this Background move
to the left until it disappears.
So we have
our RepeatBackground Script.
So we're going to go
into that Script by double-clicking.
Now in our RepeatBackground Script,
we're going to create
a variable for ourselves to make
things a bit easier.
This will be a private variable,
so we can change
it in our code if we need to later.
It'll be a Vector3,
because we actually want the position.
And in this case,
we're actually going to be getting
the position that our Object starts at.
Now, this will be very helpful,
so that we know where we
should reset our Background
when it reaches the point
that we need to put it back,
and make it look
like it's repeating.
Now what we're going to do is
actually in our Start() method,
we're going to set our "startPos,"
and we're actually just going to get
all of the coordinates
of our transform.position.
And now we need to check
to make sure
that whenever we get
to a certain position,
we can reset our Background
to go back to our start position.
So, we're going to use
an if() statement to do that check.
We're going to want to find
the current position of our Background,
so we're going to use
our transform.position.
And since our Background is
only moving on the x-axis,
that's the only position
we need to check against.
Now we want to see
whenever our current position,
becomes less than our starting position.
But specifically, we want to make
sure that our Background
is farther down the line
on our X-Axis before
we reset the position
of our Background to be
the starting position again.
So we'll just use an offset for now,
and we're just going to use 40...
I think. We'll see how that works.
And then if we create a new line,
and then we use the curly braces,
in our if() statement,
we're going to...
set our transform.position
that it's currently at,
and we're just going to reset
it back to the position
of our variable.
Now in Unity, we'll see how this works,
and how this looks. So,
whenever our current position hits
a certain point past the start position,
it'll reset itself.
That looks...
kind of okay.
It looks a little weird.
It kinda looks like the Background
is stuttering in some ways.
Let's see if we can fiddle
with that number just a little bit more,
maybe we'll set it to 50
so it's farther down the line.
So we'll change the variable to 50.
And we'll save that,
and then we'll see how that looks.
So now, hopefully our Background can go
a little bit farther down
before it resets itself.
It looks a little bit better.
It's getting almost there, but...
I think that's good
enough for now.
So what we'll do is
in your RepeatBackground Script,
you're going to create
your own variable
for a coordinate,
so you're going to use a Vector3.
And that coordinate's going to be
your start position of your Object.
In the Start() method,
we're going to set
the startPos
equal to the transform.position,
the current position of our Object,
just so that we always know exactly
where our Object started
at when it was in the scene,
and then we're going to check
in our Update() function
to see when our current position
is less than our start position,
and a little offset,
then we'll reset the entire
position of our Object
back to our startPos.
Now it's your turn.
[music]